Guide to The Leo Deaner Radical Left-Wing Publications collection, 1890-2017 LAC0011
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Pamphlets by topic, 1890-2017; Series 3
  - Geographic regions, 1890-2016; Series 3 Subseries 6
    - Geographic Regions, 1965-1967; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 127, Folder 2)
      Speech by Lawyer Nguyen Huu Tho …on the Occasion of the 5th Founding Anniversary of the N.F.L. Published by Liberation Editions; NFL of South Vietnam: the Only Genuine and Legal Representative of the South Vietnam People Published by Liberation Editions; To Thi Kieu: an Heroic Girl of Bentre by Phan Thi Nhu Bang Published by Liberation Editions; Way he Lived: the Story of Nguyen Van Troi Told by his Widow Phan Thi Quyen Written by Tran Dihn Van Published by Liberation Publishing House; 20 Years Development of Education in the Democratic Republic of Vietnam by Nguyen Khanh Toan Published by House of the Ministry of Education in the Democratic Republic of Vietnam; Ap Bac: Major Battles in South Vietnam 1963-1964 by Le Hong Linh, Vuong Thanh Dien, Nguyen Q.S. Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; In South Vietnam U.S. Biggest Operation Foiled (February-April 1967) Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Once again We will Win by Vo Nguyen Giap Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Vietnamese Problem by Luu Quy Ky Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Five Lessons of a Great Victory (Winter 1966-Spring 1967) by Truong Son Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; North Vietnamese Medicine Facing the Trial of War Edited by Nguyen Khac Vien Published by Vietnamese Studies; President Ho Chi Minh Answers President L.B. Johnson Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; American Use of War Gases and World Public Opinion Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Mr. Fourth's Dream: a Vietnamese Tale by Anh Duoc; Documents about the Collusion Between the Thailand Authorities and the U.S. Ruling Circles I the War of Aggression in Viet Nam Published by Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Democratic Republic of Viet Nam
    - Geographic Regions, 1968-1974; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 127, Folder 3)
      South Vietnam Published by Embassy of the Provisional Revolutionary Government of the Republic of South Viet Nam in Cuba; American Aircraft Systematically Attack Dams and Dikes in the D.R.V. N. Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Forward! Final Victory will be Ours! D.R.V.N. Government Report of the National Assembly, 3rd Legislature, 3rh Session, May 24, 1968) By Pham Van Dong; South Vietnam U.S. Defeat Inevitable by Van Tien Dung Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Forward under the Glorious Banner of the October Revolution: on the Occasion of the 50th Anniversary of the October Revolution, 2nd Edition by Le Duan Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; South Viet Nam: a Month of Unprecedented Offensive and Uprising Published by Giai Phong Publishing; Scenes of the General Offensive and Uprising Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; For the Century of Lenin's Birth by Truong-Chinh Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Political Program of South Vietnam National Liberation Front Reprinted by American Friends Service Committee; Problems of Revolutionary Strategy by Le Duan Published by Association of Vietnamese Patriots in Canada; Vietnam: Three Documents of the National Liberation Front (Spokesman Pamphlet no. 4); President Ho chi Minh's Testament, Appeal and Last Tribute of the Central Committee of the Viet Nam Workers' Party Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Viet Nam, no. 153 (1971)
    - Geographic Regions, 1975-1999; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 127, Folder 4)
      Thieu Regime Put to the Test, 1973-1975 Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Let our Entire People Unite to Build our Reunified Socialist Fatherland Vietnam! By Le Duan Published by Communist Party of India; Truth about Vietnam-China Relations over the last Thirty Years Published by Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Socialist Republic of Viet Nam; Vietnam Ten Years After Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Vietnam and Peace by Vietnam Peace Committee Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Vietnam 1998-1999 Published by Gioi Publishers; Vietnam-China War Published as Southeast Asia Chronicle Issue No. 68 (Dec. 1979) Published by Southeast Asia Resource Center
    - Geographic Regions, 1984-1986; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 127, Folder 5)
      Chinese Rulers' Crimes against Kampuchea Published by Ministry of Foreign Affairs, People's Republic of Kampuchea; Kampuchea: the Revolution Rescued by Irwin Sibler
    - Geographic Regions, 1964-1969; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 127, Folder 6)
      Worthy Daughters and Sons of Lao People Published by Neo Lao Haksat Publications; Programme of Action of the Neo Lao Haksat: Adopted on April 10, 1964, at the Second National Congress of the Neo Lao Haksat Published by Editions of the Neo Lao Haksat; Laos the Forgotten War by Jacques Decornoy Originally Appeared in Le Mond, July 3, 1968; Laos: Another Vietnam? [flyer]
    - Geographic Regions, 1971-1972; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 127, Folder 7)
      Operation War Shift: Position Paper, 2nd Rev. Edition Published by American-Korean Friendship and Information Center; Heroic Korean People Published by Foreign Languages Press Peiking
    - Geographic Regions, 1969; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 127, Folder 8)
      Indonesia: the Gestapu Affair by Arnold C. Brackman Published by American-Asian Educational Exchange
    - Geographic Regions, 1922-1945; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 128, Folder 1)
      Red Dragon and the Black Shirts: How Italy Found her Soul: the True Story of the Fascisti Movement by Percival Phillips; Italy Victory through Revolution by Roy Curtis Published by socialist Party (Freedom for All Pamphlet no. 2); Italy after Mussolini by John Hewetson; New Italy Arises! By Giuseppe Berti; Butcher is Dead! Issued by Communist Political Association
    - Geographic Reginos, 1966-1980; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 128, Folder 2)
      Contents in folder include publications about Israel
      Israel: the Reality behind the Myths by Lev Korneyev; Israeli Economy: a War Economy by Ibrahim M. Oweiss; Which Way Israel? An Eye-Witness Account by a Marxist Educator Hyman Lumer (New Outlook Pamphlet); Israel & South Africa, 2nd enlarged Edition by George J. Tomeh; Palestine Problem, Israel and Imperialism by Members of Israeli Socialist Organization; Zionism and the Israeli State by Larry Hochman
    - Geographic Regions, 1936-2002; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 128, Folder 3)
      Contents in folder include publications about Europe
      Foreign Wings over the Basque Country Published by Friends of Spain; Spain's War of Independence Published by Spanish Embassy, Washington, D.C.; Heroic Spain by Andre Marty Spain Defends Democracy; I Escaped from Nazi Germany: a French Deportee's Report Published by I.N.G.; Trial of the Communist Deputies in France by Gaston Richard; Spotlight on Germany: the Story behind Today's Headlines' by Paul Richards; How Mussolini Proviked the spanishCivil War: Documentary Evidence; Remembering Spain: Italian Anarchist Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War by Umberto MarzocchiExtermination and the Resistance of the Polish Jews during the Period 1939-1944 by B. Mark Published by Jewish Historical Institute; Women in Hitler's Life by Robert Arndt; Fascism/Antifascism by J. Barrot; Looking Back after Twenty Years of Jail: Questions & Answers on the Spanish Anarchist Resistance by Miguel Garcia Garcia; Italo-German Aggression against Spain: Three Speeches of Sr. Juan Negrin
    - Geographic Regions, 1946-1975; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 128, Folder 4)
      Contents in folder include publications about Philippines
      What Price Philippine Independence? By George Phillips; U.S. and the Philippines by Labor Research Association; Philippine Crisis: Background and Perspective by Juan Razon Verdad Published by Far East Reporter; National Democratic Front's Ten Point Program Published by Philippines Research Center; Philippines the next Vietnam Published by ACCESS-Philippines; Democracy Dies by Charles F. Thomson Published in the Philadelphia Bulletin January 20-24, 1974; Maguindanao: a Tribute to the Muslim Filipinos Presented by Filipino American Alliance and Katifunan (Union of Democratic Filipinos)
    - Geographic Regions, 1976-1979; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 128, Folder 5)
      U.S. Military Bases in the Philippines: Do they Serve the Philippine Natinal Interest? Published by Anti-Martial Law Coalition (Philippines); People's War in the Philippines Published by Katipunan ng mga Demokratikong Pilipino (KDP), Union of Democratic Filipinos [2 copies]; Specific Characteristics of our People's War by Amado Guerrero Published by Solidarity Publishing House; Makibaka! Revolutionary Literature from the Philippines Edited by E. San Juan, Jr. Published by Philippines Research Center; Human Rights and Martial Law I the Philippines: Report of the FFP/AMLC Investigating Mission 1977 Manila World Peace Through Law Conference Published by National Resource Center on Political Prisoners in the Philippines; Mangahas Makibaka! Mangahas Magtagumpay! By Felix Razon Published by Philippines Research Center; Philippines: Workers in the Export Industry by Enrico Paglaban Published in Pacific Research vol. 9. No. 3 & 4 (March-June 1978)
    - Gregraphic Regions, 1980-1997; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 128, Folder 6)
      A Comrade is as Precious as a Rice Seedling: Poems by Milad Aguilar; Moro People's Struggle: Documents from the Moro National Liberation Front (MNLF); Fidel Ramos, the Pentagon's Philippine Friend, 1992-1997 by Daniel B. Schirmer Published by Friends of the Filipino People; Free Jose Maria Sison, Philippine Political Prisoner Published by Philippines Research Center; Philippine Debt to Foreign Banks by John E. Lund Published by Northern California Interfaith Committee on Corporate Responsibility; Philippines after Marcos: the Unfinished Democratic Revolution Reprints form Frontline Newspaper; Marcos Fake, Hero Published by Movement for a Free Philippines; Philippine Struggle by the Central Committee of the April 6th Liberation Movement Published by Filipino Information Service; Death Squads in the Philippines Edited by Enrique Delacruz, Aida Jordan and Jorge Emmanuel Published by Alliance for Philippine Concerns; Philippine Situationer 1985 for the Campaign against Militarization in the Philippines (CAMP) 1985-86: Brutal Forms of Repression against People's Organizations Published by Komite ng Sambayanang Pilipino (Filipino People's Committee)
    - Geographic Regions, 1932-1949; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 129, Folder 1)
      Present Situation in Germany by O. Piatnitsky; Socialist Competition of the Masses by E. Mikulina with a Preface by J. Stalin Published by Co-Operatve Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the USSR; Revolutionary Crisis is Maturing: Speech by D.Z. Manuilsky at the 17th Congress of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union; Short History of the Young Communist League of the Soviet Union by A. Afonin Published by Co-Operative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the USSR; Soviet Union and World Peace by Anna Louise Strong Published by Labor Research Association (International Pamphlet no. 48); Gorky, Staunch Fighter against Fascism by Vladimir Yermilov Published by Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga; Peoples of Europe versus Hitler by B.N. Ponomarev Published by Foreign Languages Publishing (Popular Lecture Series); War and the People by K. Pollard; New Lithuania by Anna Louise Strong; National Question in the Soviet Union by M. Chekalin; Note Submitted by V. Molotov Concerning the Universal Robbery and Despoliation of the Population, and the Monstrous Atrocities Perpetrated by the German Authorities on Occupied Soviet Territory Published by Foreign Languages Publishing; Patriotic War of the Soviet People against the German Invaders by M. Kalinin Published by foreign Languages Publishing; Engineer Looks at Russia by Wal Hannington, a British-Soviet Society Publication
    - Geographic Regions, 1950-1971; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 129, Folder 2)
      Soviet Army Published by Novosti Press Agency Publishing House; Soviet Navy Published by Novosti Press Agency Publishing House; Utopian Socialism of the Nineteenth Century by G.V. Plekhanov Published by Foreign Languages Publishing (Books for Socialism); Programmatic Proclamation of the Soviet Revolutionary Communists (Bolsheviks) Published by Soviet Bolshevik Communists; Communism and Freedom of the Individual by Y. Frantsev Published by Foreign Languages Publishing House; Essays on Literature, Philosophy, and Music by Andrei A. Zhdanov
    - Geographic Regions, 1970-1976; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 129, Folder 3)
      Contents in folder include publications about Portugal
      Portugal in Revolt by Caroline Lund and Baxter Smith, Articles Reprinted from the socialist weekly, The Militant, May 10, 1974-July 5, 1974; Portugal 1970: Capitalist Strategy, Workers' Offensive and Colonial War; Portugal: Anti-Fascism or Anti-Capitalism (Root & Branch Pamphlet 6); Portugal: Revolutionary Developments April 1974-Sept. 1975 by Sam Marcy Articles Reprinted from Workers World; Portugal a Blaze of Freedom Published by Big Flame
    - Geographic Regions, 1934-2012; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 129, Folder 4)
      Ernst Thaelmann: the Leader of the German Workers; Socialism's new Beginning: a Manifesto from Underground Germany by Miles Published by League for Industrial Democracy; Nazis Preferred: the Renazification of Western Germany by Moses Miller; Signs of Awakening: the Peace Manifesto of the Rhineland Conference; How Nazi Germany has Mobilized and Controlled Labor by L. Hamburger Published by Brookings Institution; Munich Betrayal by Harry Gannes; Wild Socialism: Workers Councils in Revolutionary Berlin, 1918-21 by Martin Comack; German Problem: Roadblock to Disarmament Published by Disarmament Committee of Washington Woman Strike for Peace; Origins of the Movement for Workers Councils in Germany 1918-29 (Workers Voice Pamphlet
    - Geographic regions, 1969-1984; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 160, Folder 1)
      Materials in this folder relate to Africa: Proclamation and Recognition of the Rupublic of Ginea-Bissau; With Freedome in Their Eyes; National Front for the Liberation of Angola; Interview with the African National Congress; Only Revolution will Transform South Africa; Seminar in North America on the Efforts by the Interntaional Community to End South Africa's Illegal Occupation of Namibia; The Struggle for Mozambique; Rhodesia or Zimbabwe No Middle Ground in Africa; South Africa and IIsrael: The Apartheid Connection?; Treason Against Apartheid; Black Consciousness Movement of Azania.
    - Geographic regions, 1954-1973; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 160, Folder 2)
      Materials in this folder relate to the Soviet Union: USSR-USA Relations Today by Gromykol Shvedkov; The Socio-Political and Philosophical Views of V.G. Belinsky by Z.V. Smirnova; For Czar and Country: A History of the Russian Guard Corps, 1941-1945 by Antonio J. Munoz; People's Democracy, A New Form of Political Organization of Society; Privatization and Worker Ownership in the USSR by Jacob Keremetsky and John Logue; A Clas of Cultures Some Contrasts in American and Soviet Morals and Manners by Vivian and Vincent Hallinan; The Unions and the Socialists by Leo Krzychi; On the Sure Road to New Victories by G.M. Malenkov; Soviet Froeign Relations by V.M. Molotov; The Bolshevicks and the Soviets by Albert Rhys Williams; To Illuminate the Darkness; Life and Labor in the Soviet Union by Robert Dunn and George Wallace; Perestroiaka: the Revolution Continues; One Year of Soviet Struggle Against German Invasion.
    - Geographic regions, 1974-1978; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 160, Folder 3)
      The materials in this folder relate to Africa: Against Apartheid and Colonialism in Africa; From Slavery to Freedom: A Story from Angola: Revolutionary Pressure in Africa by Claude Ake; The Last to Leave: Portuguese Colonialism in Africa by Bruno da Ponte; Namibia: The Facts; Interview with Dr. Americo Boavida; Guerrilla Warfare; Sharpeville and After Supression and Liberation in Southern Africa; Application of 'Internationally Acceptable Solution' to Namibia Today; Revolution in the Congo by Dick Roberts; The powers behind apartheid by G. Fasulo; African Leadership and European Domination; Social Classes and Political Struggle in Africa by Romano Ledda.
    - Geographic regions, 1976-2007; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 160, Folder 4)
      Materials in this folder relate to Africa: Seeing is Believing - Here is the Truth; Stanley's Explots, or Civilising Africa by D.J. Nicoll; The South African Workers' Struggle; Worker's Struggle for Freedom; Looking Forward; Remember Kassinga; African Workers and Apartheid by David Davis; Basebetsi Mekoting Mine Workers Conditions in South Africa; Workers in Chains; The Other Congo Story by Edward Chukukere; South Africa Act I of the Revolution by Glenn Wolfe; Namibia by Winifred Courtney and Jennifer Davis; Future Lies in a Progressive Biafra; When the War Ends.
    - Geographic regions, 1985-2005; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 161, Folder 1)
      Materials in this folder relate to Central America: Guatemala's Femicides and the Ongoing Struggle for Women's Human Rights; Fired for Crying to the Gringos; Forced to Move; El Salvador 1985: Health, Human Rights, and the War; El Salvador The Other War by Tom Barry and Deb Preusch; U.S. Military Involvement in El Salvador 1947-1980; The Revolution in Peru is profoundly liberating; Center for Gender and Refugee Studies; The Indian-Sandinista War in Nicaragua by Yolanda Alaniz; Nicaragua by Arnold Weissberg; Soft Drink Hard Labor.
    - Geographic regions, 1965-1998; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 161, Folder 2)
      The materials in this folder relate to Yugoslavia: The Truth about Yugoslavia by George Fyson; Against Nato's War in Yugoslavia; An Appeal to Yugoslavian Workers; Struggle Against Titoism; Two Articles on Yugoslavia; The Yugoslavian Front Against Fascism by Mirko Markovich; Rebuilding Yugoslavia by A. Gelach; Yugoslavaia at Crossroads; The Truth about Yugoslavia; Why did the students revolt in Yugoslavia?.
    - Geographic regions, 1942-1970; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 161, Folder 3)
      Materials in this folder relate to Czechoslavakia: The Czechoslavak Frame-Up Trials by Caroline Lund; Czechoslavakia and the Counter-Revolution by Herbert Aptheker; Czechoslavakiaand the World Crisis by Maxim Litvinov; Notes from the Gallows by Julius Fuchik; Czechoslavak Sources and Documents; Political Prisoners in Czechoslavakia and the USSR; The Invasion of Czechoslavakia; The Lessons of Czechoslavakia by Robert Spivack.
    - Geographic regions, 1931-1977; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 161, Folder 4)
      The materials in this folder relate to South Asia: Conditions among the working classes in India by Hermman Frisch; Led by Mahatma Gandhi by Wilfred Wellock; The Revolution in India; Peshawar: Men Versus Machine Gun; Some Urgent Problems of the Labor Movement in India by V. Basak; Tapol; Republic of Indonesia by Dr. Soekarno; Dictatorship in India.
    - Geographic regions, 1970-1980; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 162, Folder 1)
      The material in this folder relate to Puerto Rico: Support the Dellums Bill; Dellums Revolution; The Young Lords Ramparts; Vieques: Jornada; People's War in Puerto Rico; Obreros en Marcha.
    - Geographic regions, 1976-2004; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 162, Folder 2)
      Materials in this folder relate to Latin America: Chile the Road to Disaster; The Intensification of Independence in Wallmapu by John Serverino; The Struggle for Liberation in Brazil by Luis Carlos Prestes; U.S. Over Latin America by Herman Olden; The Venezuelan Revolution; With the Chilean People Against Fascism!; The Tupamaros; The US and Chile.
    - Geographic regions, 1980-1985; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 162, Folder 3)
      Materials in this folder relate to Iran: Women and Struggle in Iran; Women and Struggle in Iran No. 4; 100 Years of Modern Iran; On the Alliance of the October League with the Shah of Iran; Hadi Never Died; The Recent Events in Iran and Our Position; Iran the Unfolding Revolution; Imperialism vs. the Iranian Revolution by Janice Lynn and David Frankel; Peykar; Peykar; Tudeh Party.
    - Geographic regions, 1973-1976; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 162, Folder 4)
      Material in this folder relate to the PPhilippines: Information Bulletin Vol. III No. 4; Information Bulletin Vol. I No. 2; Reform or Revolution by Roberto Pumarada; Information Bulletin Vol. IV No. 1; Political Detainees in the Philippines; Testimony on Human Rights in the Philippines; Dare to Struggle Dare to Win! by Clarita Roja; What's Happening in the Philippines? by Samuel P. Bayani; Democracy in Form, Dictatorship in Substance; Unite to overthrow the U.S.-Marcos dictatorship; Sigaboy; Ten-Point Program of the National Democratic Front; Political Prisoners in the Philippines; Filipino Workers Strike at Repression.
    - Geographic regions, 1963-1965; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 162, Folder 5)
      Materials in this folder relate to Berkeley: Education in the University; neighborhood food newsletter; Disorientation; Slate Supplement to the General Catalog; The Berkeley Teacher's Strike and Beyond by Richard Broadhead.
    - Geographic regions, 1962-1977; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 163, Folder 3)
      Materials in this folder relate to Berkeley: Berkeley in the Sixties; Disorientation week; The Regents; California Dynasty of Communism by Karl Prussion; Protect the Earth by Thomas Parkinson; The Regents by Marvin Garson.
    - Geographic regions, 1964-1980; Series 3 Subseries 6 (Box 163, Folder 4)
      The materials in this folder relate to Berkeley: APril Coalition Platform; Students in Revolt; Man and State by Harry Epstein and David Levy; The Battle of Berkeley; Everyone's Guide to Rent Stabilization in Berkeley; Whole Berkeley Catalogue; Disorientation.
    - Geographic Regions, 1956-2006; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 178, Folder 1)
      Content in this folder relate to India
      People's War... Women's War?; Who Owns India; Peasants Meet at Moga; India in Revolt; Kashmir; Soviet Social Imperialism In India; Cruel and Vicious Repression of Myanmar Peoples by Imperialists and Fascists and the True Story About the Plunder of the Royal Jewels; The Kashmir Question; To the Workers and Peasants of India; Ceylon: the JVP Uprising of April 1971; Revolutionary Marxism vs. Class Collaboration in Sri Lanka; Ceylon the great betrayal.
    - Geographic Regions, 1974-1985; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 178, Folder 2)
      Content in this folder relate to Latin America
      Revolution in Peru; Revolution in Peru; Supysaua A Documentary Report on the Conditions of Indian Peoples in Brazil; The Indian Situation in Brazil Today; The Rights of Indigenous Women in Columbia.
    - Geographic Regions, 1973-1983; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 178, Folder 3)
      What is the MIR? Notes on the History of MIR; Strange Defeat; Che Lives; A Nation in Protest Chile 1983; Mini Manual of the Urban Guerrilla; Venezuela The revolution unfolding in Latin America; In the Hands of Chile's Hangmen; New Testimonies to the Crimes of the Military Junta in Chile.
    - Geographic Regions, 1975; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 178, Folder 4)
      Seven Issues of Resistance Courier.
    - Geographic Regions, 1956-1965; Series 3 Subseries 5 (Box 178, Folder 5)
      Content in this folder relate to Portugal/France